Why, that's a cute little kitten, Ioryogi-san
We can no longer care for her.
Please take her home.
Don't go sticking your nose into
something you can't handle.
She's fluffy!
Were you listening to even a word I said?
I cannot leave the kitten alone.
Well then, what do you plan on doing?
Let me care for her.
I'm going to do this.
This way the kitten will not be lonely and I
will be able to find someone for her.
Do you plan to live here forever?!
Kobato.
Dou sureba iin dakke?
Atarimae no kototte itsumo
Muzukashii na
Ureshii toki waratte
Suki na toki ni utaitai dake
Na no ni
Itsuka negai wa kanau to
Demo "itsuka" tte dore kurai?
Machikirenai yo
123! no aizu de ryoute hirogete
Zenshin ni hikari wo atsumete
Doko ni aru no?
Oshiete, watashi ni dekiru koto
Meippai kizu tsuite
Seiippai hashitte
Nan juu kai koronde naite
Sore de mo mada
Akireru kurai
Ashita wo shinjiteru
...A Kitten's Lullaby.
You can't even look after yourself.
How do you expect to look after a cat?
But I can't leave her like that.
So now an abandoned cat?
No way. The cat's owner can
no longer care for her.
That's the same.
If you don't intend to care for her to
the end, don't get involved.
He's mean.
He's absolutely right.
What's the matter, Kitten?
I-I wonder what's wrong!
She's probably hungry.
Huh?!
Hanamaro Drill
Arithmetic
What's the answer to number five, Chiho?
What? You don't know either, Chise?
Yes!
Oh.
It's Kobato.
Hello.
I was hoping you could
satisfy a hungry stomach!
Mother isn't here right now.
This is all we have.
U-Um, I don't think this would work as a meal.
Huh?
Oh, I mean, not for me, but...
It's for this little kitten.
Wow!
So cute!
The owner isn't able to look
after her anymore and...
I was hoping you had
something I could feed her.
Shhh!
Can we come to your room, Kobato?
Sure.
She seems to like it.
Good.
Um, why are you two whispering?
Huh? Huh?
Pets are not allowed in this building.
A person living here before had a dog and
neighbors complained about the barking.
So...
Mother decided not to accept
new residents with pets.
Which would mean we can't look after her here.
Why don't you ask the owner again?
I don't know who that is.
The kitten was left in a box and the owner's
name wasn't written on it anywhere.
Is that right. But at this rate,
the kitten's going to end up all alone.
If only there's someone who would
agree to take care of her.
I'll ask Ms. Sayaka at the kindergarten tomorrow.
I'm sure that Ms. Sayaka will say yes.
If she's at Yomogi Kindergarten,
we can visit her any time.
Then we'd better name her.
What do you think, Kobato?
What, me?
U-Um...
It's too sudden, I can't think!
How about "Milk" 'cause she's pure white.
And she loves milk.
Milk. That's a cute name. It's nice.
Yomogi Kindergarten
Oh so cute!
She's pure white!
I hear her name's Milk!
Milk, come over here!
Let me hold her!
Me too!
Let me touch her.
Everyone seems happy.
So can you keep her here?
Yuzuru.
Come over here for a minute.
Are you all right?
Yuzuru. You might be allergic to cats.
Allergic... to cats?
Like with him, allergic people can
start sneezing or get rashes.
If it worsens, it can lead to asthma.
Ms. Sayaka.
We can't keep a cat at the kindergarten.
You're right.
I'm sorry, Kobato.
You end up hurting people when you act
without thinking things through.
I wasn't acting without thinking!
Then can you take responsibility?
Fujimoto!
If you're only taking care of it
half-heartedly to satisfy yourself,
you're just as guilty as the
people who abandoned it.
I'm sorry, Kobato.
I'm alright now, though.
No, I'm sorry.
Hey, stop that!
Get away from me! I'm a stuffed
doll but I'm not a stuffed doll!
Kobato, you're here.
Ms. Sayaka.
Can I sit next to you?
Please.
I'm sorry to have disappointed you.
Oh, no. I should be the one apologizing.
Fujimoto doesn't mean ill, you know.
I think he compares himself
to that kitten in some ways.
What?
Oh nothing. I'll help you find
someone to look after the kitten.
Don't worry, we'll find someone, I'm sure.
Yes.
So what do you expect to do now?
I will find someone who can look after Milk.
I cannot cause any more trouble!
I agree.
I've also been troubled enough.
Bye-bye.
Ms. Sayaka.
Hello.
Is Milk here?
Allergic to cats?
I'm afraid so. I'm sorry.
It's all right.
Should we talk to Mother?
No. Pets are not allowed.
If we said anything, we'd just make her sad.
You're right.
Can anybody take care of this kitten?!
Please take this kitten home with you!
Look after her, please...
Kobato!
Chiho, Chise.
Hi there, Milk!
Have you been a good girl?
I'm sorry. I asked Ms. Sayaka, but...
We went to the kindergarten.
Huh?
It's not your fault, Kobato.
But I haven't been able to find anyone yet.
We'll help you.
Milk. We'll be sure to find
someone to take care of you.
I'm sorry.
My own children are a handful as it is.
Oh my, Katherine, what's the matter dear?
Kobato.
Let's go.
Um, excuse me!
Get out of my face! I hate sales people!
Huh?
Milk!
Hey, what the...
Domoto.
Kobato?
Milk!
Come here!
Oh, wow! That's great!
So you need someone to take that kitten.
Yes.
My friends all live alone, so I can't think
of anyone off the top of my head,
but I'll see if I can find someone.
Thank you so much. I seem to be causing
everyone a lot of trouble.
I don't think that at all. You're trying so hard.
So we all want to be of help.
No, really...
But you probably should stop
going to strangers' homes.
But Fujimoto told me, " If you're only taking care
of it half-heartedly to satisfy yourself,
you're just like the people who abandoned it".
That's just him. Don't worry about it.
I don't think that anyone would really
want to abandon such a cute kitten.
There must have been a reason.
But when Fujimoto said that,
he looked really lonely.
But he's right. I mustn't tackle this
half-heartedly. I will do everything I can.
Ah, but next time I'll go to homes
where I know the people.
Well then, if you need to reach me,
here's my cell number. Call me.
Okay! Thank you very much.
I guess nobody's home.
They're closed.
Hmm... Well you know I handle food.
I can't be having a cat around here.
Is that right.
Sorry I can't help you.
Hello? Mihara residence. Sayaka?
What? A kitten?
I would really like to be able to keep it here but...
The children said that?
Okay. I understand. Thanks.
Oh?
It's getting pretty dark.
Milk's getting tired, too.
Milk?
She must be hungry.
Ready, set...
This one.
I can't do anything. I feel so ridiculous.
Yeah, you can't even buy food for the cat.
No...
Hey Chise.
What is it?
Let's ask Mother anyway.
Yes, I think Mother will understand.
Then we can sleep with Milk tonight.
Mhm. Let's sleep together. You too, Kobato.
Yes.
That lady from...
Oh.
The girl with the pretty singing voice.
Kobato, do you know her?
Yes. Um, where's the baby?
Oh her mother has the day off today,
so she's at home with her.
Oh I see.
But what are you doing here?
I heard there was a girl looking for
someone to take care of a kitten.
What?
Oh my.
This is the kitten, isn't it?
How tiny and cute.
If you don't mind, I'd like to take
her home and care for her.
Really?!
Yes. My grandchild is an only child and I'm sure
she'd be thrilled to have a little playmate.
Oh but...
Some people sneeze or cough when they
touch the kitten. Is the baby okay?
That pizza man was worried
about the same thing.
Pizza man?
Yes. He was asking at every house he delivered
pizzas to, if they could care for a kitten.
I overheard him, and that's what
led me to come here.
That's Fujimoto.
My grandchild loves animals.
And she isn't allergic to cats.
Oh, look...
Aren't you lucky, Milk?
You're going to have a nice home.
Good night.
Bye-bye, Milk.
We'll come and visit.
Please wait, ma'am.
This is Milk's food.
My... Yes indeed. Thank you.
Please take good care of Milk.
Y-Yes, please.
This room feels very big without Milk.
Yeah!
Good riddance!
What's this?
Milk's milk dish.
I'm sure that Chiho and Chise
are feeling the same way.
Where are you going?
Kobato.
G-Good evening.
Um...
Chiho and Chise are up on the roof.
I wonder if they're taking good care of Milk.
She seemed like a nice grandmother.
Milk is in good hands with that grandmother.
Kobato?
Oh, that...
I forgot to return it to you.
Milk's...
...milk dish.
Yes.
Come to think of it, there was a full moon like
tonight the night I first met that grandmother.
The cherry blossoms were beautiful.
The grandmother was with a baby
who wouldn't stop crying.
I tried to cuddle the baby too.
But then she cried even louder!
And then?
What did you do?
Then I sang her a song.
Huh?
You sang, Kobato?
Yes. And then the baby stopped crying.
What kind of song did you sing?
Huh?
Uh, well...
I'd like to hear it!
Me too!
Huh?
Can you sing it for us, Kobato?
Please.
Okay.
Flowers blossom in the spring
Skies in the summer reach far and wide
Every time I think of this
Precious thoughts spread across in my heart
In the morning when it rains
This song...
On those days when the windows stay closed
My heart shimmers with the light
Light shining brightly above the clouds
The voices are calling to me
From way over yonder, from far I can hear
Voices of laughter
Voices of singing
Echoing voices of the wind
In happiness and in sadness
In all I behold and all that I live for
With my hand in your hand
Your hand in my hand
Together, we are one and whole
What is it?
Thank you for your help regarding Milk.
The kitten has found a wonderful home.
Thanks to you, Fujimoto.
Is that all you came for?
Yes.
What are you doing?!
I remembered something very important!
May I borrow your phone?
So if you come across anyone who likes
cats, let me know. Yeah. Thank you.
Kiyokazu Fujimoto
Fujimoto?
Hello?
Um... um... well...
Huh? Kobato? What's up?
Yes, uh, um... We found someone
who will take care of the kitten.
I just wanted to let you know.
Oh.
Yes. Fujimoto found someone.
Fujimoto did?
Really.
Sorry to cause all the worry.
No, that's good. See you.
There's more.
But why is there more?
Fujimoto is the one who
found a new home for Milk.
I wasn't any help at all.
Not only that! Because you brought the cat
in here, you caused all sorts of trouble!
Yes. It was all my fault. I caused
everybody a lot of worry and trouble.
Well, you give some you take some.
That's what life's about.
Huh?
You sang for Chiho and Chise because you
realized how lonely they were feeling
after parting with the kitten.
I just wanted to tell them about
that grandmother and the baby.
And I guess you made them
feel better by doing that.
So singing can sometimes be
soothing to the heart too.
But you know... my injured ear has not healed!
Therefore.
Kobato you have zero points!
What?!
Oh, but it's round. Just like today's moon.
This isn't the time to rejoice!
Come to think of it, Milk's dish is round, too.
We're all matching!
All right then, if you like the circle so much,
I'll give you zero every time from now on!
What?! Ioryogi-san, you are so mean!
Hito wa mina tonde mitai no ni
Juuryoku ni damasareterunda
Dare mo honto wa toberunda yo
Ano ko ga anna ni kanashisou na no wa
Jibun no kage wo
Dokoka ni wasurete kichatta kara kamo
Sore nara
"Arigatou," tte kimi ni ietara
"Arigatou," tte kimi ga waraeba
Ittari kitari ureshiku naru
Kimi ga shiawase ni naru
Shinpai nante iranai yo
Issho ni iru kara
Ureshikuttemo namida ga deru nante
Fushigi da
Next episode
...Memories of Summer.
Fushigi da
Next episode
...Memories of Summer.